export const SOCIALSTUDIESA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "1. Which of the following statements l›est c.xpIains selfconcepf? The",
A: "inborn characteristics ofa person",
B: "personal and physiological abilities ofa person",
C: "physical aitd ysychomotor nature ofa person",
D: "whole nature ofa person",
answer: "D. Whole nature of a person",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "2. The basic level of Abraham Maslow’s 1*h.o	or x»a	in",
A: "physiological.",
B: "safely.",
C: "sell-actualization.",
D: "social.",
answer: "A. Physiological",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "3. Which of thc follo›vii›g statenzenis is accurate about praclisin'z ch.t.xlif/ .I tii4 :â‹I‹âIL'.*sL'fil1i\’",
A: "Absence of risks related to se.xuaI activities",
B: "Becoming sext›all}' inc.xpcricnccd in marital like",
C: "Keeping your sexuality confidential mom everybody",
D: "Preserving one*s cncryy ior ’ork",
answer: "A. Absence of risks related to sexual activities",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "4. To foster good gender relations in Ghana. tliuic is the need to",
A: "discourage discrimination against women.",
B: "establish more single-se.x schools.",
C: "expunge laws on violence against women.",
D: "make reproductive concenis the sole responsibility or women.",
answer: "A. Discourage discrimination against women",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "5. Which of the following statements is not accurate ahout sonic Gl›aMaian cciltural practices?",
A: "Celebration of festivals facilitate clean-uy ol“cominunitics",
B: "Chieftaincy promotes traditional heritage",
C: "Female genital mutilation ensures chastity o/the adolescent girl",
D: "Naming ceremony promotes communal living",
answer: "C. Female genital mutilation ensures chastity of the adolescent girl",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "6. Which of the following is not a symbol of national identity in Ghana?",
A: "National Anthem",
B: "Flag of Ghana",
C: "Coat of Arms of Ghana",
D: "Adinkra patterns",
answer: "D. Adinkra patterns",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "7. One significance of socialization is diat it enablcs tl c it dividual to acquirc",
A: "cultural values.",
B: "social status.",
C: "popularip•.",
D: "prestige.",
answer: "A. Cultural values",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "8. Which of the following types of marriage is the found.atioii of all otlicr liiarri scs in Glialia‘?",
A: "Concubines contracts",
B: "Marriage by Ordinance",
C: "Customary marriage",
D: "Rel'siousmarriage",
answer: "C. Customary marriage",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "9. Couples who want to sustain their marriages should always",
A: "avoid pointing oul the mistakes oreach otlicr.",
B: "hide their past lifestyles from cach other.",
C: "maintain constant contt itiizicalioi with cach otlicr.",
D: "report each others bclinviour Io his or I cr parents.",
answer: "C. Maintain constant communication with each other",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "10. Which of the follou'ing options insist not be pursued as a purpose of marriage in the Ghanaian socieq'?",
A: "A means for file couple io provide support for cacti other",
B: "As enue for companionship arsons the couples",
C: "Provision of opportunity to have sc.xual relations with anybody",
D: "Provision of legitimate avenue for procreation",
answer: "C. Provision of opportunity to have sexual relations with anybody",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "11. The Intestate Succession Law in Ghana »'as promulgated to",
A: "allow the deceased's nephe»'s to inherit property.",
B: "allow the survivitig spouse to share the property.",
C: "enable the extended family to control ilie property.",
D: "enable survivors get their share of ihe property.",
answer: "D. Enable survivors get their share of the property",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. A group of people who are related through birth, marriage and adoption is described as",
A: "community.",
B: "couple.",
C: "family.",
D: "society.",
answer: "C. Family",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "13. Parenthood stans as soon as a child is",
A: "adopted.",
B: "born.",
C: "conceived.",
D: "named.",
answer: "C. Conceived",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. The agency that is responsible for the primary socialization of the child is the",
A: "extended family.",
B: "matrilineal family.",
C: "nuclear family.",
D: "patrilineal family.",
answer: "C. Nuclear family",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. Better interpersonal relationship can be achieved in a society through the existence of",
A: "civil rights.",
B: "democratic ideas.",
C: "gender equality.",
D: "common religion.",
answer: "A. Civil rights",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. which of the following aclivitics is dctriincntal lo tl›c cnvironment?",
A: "AlTorcstation",
B: "Aqua culture",
C: "Busl› buniing",
D: "Irrigalion",
answer: "C. Bush burning",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. Which ofthe follo›ving statcinenls best describcs the physical environment? The",
A: "buildings and other sir icttires in our comnzunities",
B: "Iai›dFonnS, Ycg¢tâtioll 2nd cliinatic conditions",
C: "n ountains, lo›vlaiids and rivers in our communities",
D: "e.xtemal surroundings vitl›in vhich all living thiogs live",
answer: "D. External surroundings within which all living things live",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. A significant alteration of the structures of society that brings about dilTerences in the lives oftl›e people is referred to as",
A: "community dcvelopment.",
B: "national growth.",
C: "social change.",
D: "sustoinable development.",
answer: "C. Social change",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "19. The main aim of fonnal education is to",
A: "help the individual secure a well-paidjob.",
B: "make the individual fit well in the society.",
C: "provide the individual with higher academic excellence.",
D: "provide the individual with occupational skills.",
answer: "B. Make the individual fit well in the society",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. One responsibility that our political independence has placed on us as Ghanaians is to",
A: "always carry our complains to people in authority.",
B: "demonstrate our willingness to solve national problems.",
C: "show lukewarm attitude to duty and demand for our rights.",
D: "plan national development fron local communities.",
answer: "B. Demonstrate our willingness to solve national problems",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "21. The ability to depend mainl3' on one's own resources for survival is referred to as",
A: "economic independence.",
B: "self-actualization.",
C: "self-reliance.",
D: "political independcnce.",
answer: "C. Self-reliance",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "22. to become independent anJ self-reliant in society, lltc inJivid ial nccds to a›’oid",
A: "developing one's sell*nnJ heiiq productive.",
B: "engaging in IiarJ wnrk iu improve cite'.s life.",
C: "living in isol:ulimi Fr ›i›J nilicrs.",
D: "voting For people hclicvc‹I Io ldc cfi cti •c.",
answer: "C. Living in isolation from others",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "23. .",
A: "**********",
B: "**********",
C: "**********",
D: "**********",
answer: "A. Democratic governance",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "24. Which of  the follow iiip liiclors is",
A: "**********",
B: "**********",
C: "**********",
D: "**********",
answer: "C. Loss of lives and property",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "25. Leadership is best e.xpIaincd as l›aviiq; the outltorily to",
A: "dctcm inc ›vlial should hapycn lo followci's.",
B: "guide Otf1CF5 tOW2rds Ihc nttainmcnt of a group’s objectives.",
C: "guidc others towards the attainment of oizu*s objectives.",
D: "usc con muMity resources as one decins fit.",
answer: "B. Guide others towards the attainment of a group's objectives",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. One unique attribute of a leader is the",
A: "exercise of absolute power over followers.",
B: "insistence on followers allegiance.",
C: "reliance on followers for direction.",
D: "respect for the opinions of followers.",
answer: "C. Bush burning",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "27. A leader who relies solely on the followers for decision-making is",
A: "autocratic.",
B: "democratic.",
C: "laissez-faire.",
D: "paternalistic.",
answer: "C. Laissez-faire",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "28. Which of the following constitutional provisions prevents autocratic rule?",
A: "A free press without limitation",
B: "A judiciary free from checks and balances",
C: "Formation of more political parties",
D: "Rule of law and separation of powers",
answer: "D. Rule of law and separation of powers",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. A feature of democratic governance that is necessary for stability :•n a nation is",
A: "existence of regular army.",
B: "flamboyant appearance of politicians.",
C: "peacef\JI transition of power.",
D: "provision of social amenities.",
answer: "C. Peaceful transition of power",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "30. One reason for which unity and development are more sustainable under democratic governance is that",
A: "governments reward comm unities that vote for them with projects.",
B: "it promotes smooth and peaceful change of government.",
C: "only views of members of the ruling party are accommodated.",
D: "rules agreed upon are binding on political leaders.",
answer: "B. It promotes smooth and peaceful change of government",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "31. Rights and responsibilities ofcilizens arc",
A: "comprehensive.",
B: "**********",
C: "rcciprocal.",
D: "synonymous.",
answer: "C. Reciprocal",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. A consumer must be willing to fiillil his oi I cr rcs;›nltsihility nFpiq’ii g electricity hill",
A: "anytime the cost of living is higl›.",
B: "even wlten power supply is irrcgciI:ir.",
C: "only vlieit sinnd:ml nd liviiit} is hitch.",
D: "only widen hic individual is Jcbi-ri‹l‹len.",
answer: "B. Even when power supply is irregular",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. I ltc sitiint ioit whcre lire ›vorI‹I is lacnmiiq; cI‹›scr in Icritts nFcc‹›nnitiic anul ctilt mal dcvclopment tltrcuglJ iMzprnvtd IeclinoIt›gy ›tn‹l c‹›inm inicnlioit is r«£erred tc› as",
A: "glohal cc‹›iionty,",
B: "global x'iIIage.",
C: "co-opernlioii.",
D: "globalization.",
answer: "D. Globalization",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. One bencfit Ghana dcrives from co-operating xx'itI other natiOTlS iS that, she",
A: "expands her trade ties.",
B: "enjoys minimum utilization of resources.",
C: "enjoys autonomy from them.",
D: "dictates development plans for them.",
answer: "A. Expands her trade ties",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. A primary function of financial institutions in the country is",
A: "doubling money for customers.",
B: "orsanizing workshops for custoincrs.",
C: "sharins dividende to customers.",
D: "taking deposils and lending out nonies.",
answer: "D. Taking deposits and lending out monies",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. The quantitative and qualitative iinprovenient in the standard of living of peolpe in the society is tenned",
A: "change.",
B: "development.",
C: "groivth.",
D: "transformation.",
answer: "B. Development",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. The movement of the youth to the cities to seek for jobs can result in",
A: "creating more avenues for em ployrnent.",
B: "enhancing h iglier productivity in the villages.",
C: "denying them of economic freedom.",
D: "weakening their socialization pi ocess.",
answer: "D. Weakening their socialization process",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. The best way of promoting the application of science and teclinolo•gy in our national development process is through the",
A: "invitation of foreign scientists and technologists to solve our problems.",
B: "establishment of national science research fund.",
C: "sponsorship of more Ghanaians to study science and technology abroad.",
D: "funding the commercialization of science and technological innovations.",
answer: "D. Funding the commercialization of science and technological innovations",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. Anything that is available to society and is used for lhe production of goods and services to satisfy societal needs is",
A: "capital.",
B: "goods.",
C: "material.",
D: "resource.",
answer: "D. Resource",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. Which of the following community projects is worth undertaking in a locality prone to outbreak of diarrhoea and cholera?",
A: "Building orcommunily centre",
B: "Construction of community library",
C: "Construction of more schools",
D: "Sinking of borcholes",
answer: "D. Sinking of boreholes",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "41. Which of the following options is not a stistainahle way of ilnproving the standard of living of Ghanaians†",
A: "Provision of quality and accessible education",
B: "developing good transport and coiiiiiiiin ic.at ioii systems",
C: "Giving money lo poor households iii the coiititry",
D: "lmprovemenl in the quality of health delivery",
answer: "C. Giving money to poor households in the country",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. A major development challenge Glianaians must resolvc to addrcss is",
A: "inadequate earnings and savings.",
B: "inadequate natJJral resources.",
C: "low illiteracy rate.",
D: "low productivity in the private sector.",
answer: "A. Inadequate earnings and savings",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. The youth can best contribute to national development throiigh",
A: "early marriages to increase labour force.",
B: "effective decision-making skills.",
C: "making provisions for savings.",
D: "putting pressure on leaders for their needs.",
answer: "B. Effective decision-making skills",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. One major benefit of sustainable development is",
A: "expansion of settlements.",
B: "real ination of social peace.",
C: "exportation of human resource.",
D: "achievement of high moral standards.",
answer: "B. Realization of social peace",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. A factor that does not coMtrihute to national dcvelopiTient in Ghana is",
A: "implementation ofpriot ity projccts.",
B: "importation of food and other needs.",
C: "protection of national assets.",
D: "regular maintenance culture.",
answer: "B. Importation of good and other needs",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "46. faClOf is'li ich can hinder the sustainability of growth and development in Ghana is",
A: "contracting loans for all projects.",
B: "importing specialized machinery.",
C: "the inLux of foreign expeias.",
D: "the lack of ma iiitenancc culture.",
answer: "D. The lack of maintenance culture",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. Wh;' i as Ghana‘s poJiulation described as youthful from the 2000 population census?",
A: "Age group 15-64 represented 5.1 % of the entire population",
B: "Age 1.5 and above represented 54 % of the entire population",
C: "60 % of the population was made up of people above 20 years",
D: "45 % of the population was under the age of 15",
answer: "A. Age group 15 - 64 represented 51% of the entire population",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. Which of the following qualities can lnake an entrepreneur successful?",
A: "Drive, provision of capital and supervision",
B: "Evaltlation. flexibility and diligence",
C: "Organixatioii, co-tirdination and risk bearing",
D: "Vision. courage and good judgement",
answer: "D. Vision, courage and good judgement",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. lncrcasc in the gcneral output levels of goods and services over a period of time would lead to",
A: "physical developiT em.",
B: "political development.",
C: "social develnpmenl.",
D: "economic development.",
answer: "D. Sinking of boreholes",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. A country with laryc population sizc enjnys 1iic hcnelil nd",
A: "sk illctl labour.",
B: "l'argc market.",
C: "huge inlcrnatiniial support.",
D: "cffcct ivc use r›F I uso ii cus.",
answer: "B. Large market",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},



]